Welcome to this tutorial on successfully
logging into the application! In this
video, you'll learn how to navigate
through the login process using valid
credentials for a seamless entry to your
dashboard.
How to do it: We'll start by navigating
to the login page, enter our credentials,
and finally verify that we're welcomed
into our dashboard.
First, you'll want to navigate to the
login page by entering the URL
'http://localhost:5001/login' in your
browser. This is where you'll begin the
process. Give this a couple of seconds to
load completely.
Once the page has loaded, wait for the
email input field to appear. It's
that this area is visible before
proceeding. This might take a second.
Now, click into the email field and type
'demo@example.com'. This input is crucial
as it identifies who you are in the
system.
Next, move to the password field and
enter 'password123'. Make sure your typing
accurate here to avoid errors.
With your credentials filled in, click
the 'Submit' button to advance. This tells
the system to process your login
information.
After submitting, wait for the transition
to the dashboard to confirm a successful
login. This redirection indicates you've
been authenticated.
Finally, check for the welcome message on
your dashboard. The message should read,
'Welcome back, Demo! You have
successfully logged in.' This verifies
successful.
And that's it! You've now seen how to log
into the application seamlessly.
Following these steps ensures you can
access your dashboard quickly and
every time.